Bess Lomax Hawes collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series I: Manuscripts, Note: Some of Hawes’s San Fernando Valley State College (SFVSC) students’ papers are included in the series, though most are in the Bess Lomax Hawes Student Folklore Collection at the California State University, Northridge (formerly SFVSC).
  - SFVSC – student papers, organized alphabetically by song: P, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 18.07)
  - Films -- general, 1964-1987, Regarding distribution of Georgia Sea Island Singers (1964), Buckdancer (1965) and Say Old Man Can You Play the Fiddle (1970), and Pizza Pizza Daddy-O (1967) (Box-folder 18.08)
  - The Films of Bess Lomax Hawes, 2003, Written introduction to the films of Bess Lomax Hawes: Georgia Sea Island Singers (1964), Buckdancer (1965), Pizza Pizza Daddy-O (1967) and Say Old Man Can You Play the Fiddle (1970) (Box-folder 18.09)
  - Pizza Pizza Daddy-O legal matters/ownership, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 18.10)
  - Pizza Pizza Daddy-O (1969), 1969-1975 (Box-folder 18.11)
  - Film -- Discovering American Folk Music, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 18.12)
  - Sea Island footage, 1970-1974, Includes copies of Sing Out that contain contributions from Bess Lomax Hawes, and includes references to Buckdancer, "Bright Star Shining in Glory" and "Yonder Comes Day" projects (Box-folder 18.13)
  - Sea Island Singers -- research and brochures, 1969-1974, Correspondence reflects Bess Lomax Hawes's role on Sing Out's advisory board (Box-folder 18.14)
  - Sea Island Singers -- correspondence, 1967-1980, Includes a great deal of correspondence with Bessie Jones (Box-folder 18.15)
  - Sing Out, 1956-1961, Includes copies of Sing Out that include contributions from Bess Lomax Hawes (Box-folder 19.01)
  - Sing Out, 1982-1999, Correspondence reflects Bess Lomax Hawes's role on Sing Out's advisory board (Box-folder 19.02)
  - La Llorona in juvenile hall, 1968, Article published in Western Folklore, July 1968 (Box-folder 19.03)
  - "Happy Birthday" read at American Folklore Society meeting, 1970 (Box-folder 19.04)
  - "Happy Birthday to You" research, circa 1970 (Box-folder 19.05)
  - "Happy Birthday to You" research paper, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 19.06)
  - "Happy Birthday to You" research paper, circa 1970-1998, Includes draft of presentation given at California State University, Northridge (Box-folder 19.07)
  - "Law and order on the playground," 1968-1972 (Box-folder 19.08)
  - "Law and order on the playground," 1968-1975 (Box-folder 19.09)
  - "Folk teaching technique and learning a traditional style," 1971, Draft for California Folklore Society presentation (Box-folder 19.10)
  - San Francisquito Dam disaster corrido, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 19.11)
  - San Francisquito Dam corrido, 1974 (Box-folder 19.12)
  - "Folksongs and function: lullaby" (1 of 2), 1970-1974, Published in Journal of American Folklore, April-June 1974 (Box-folder 19.13)
  - "Folksongs and function: lullaby" (2 of 2), 1970-1974 (Box-folder 20.01)
  - Society for Ethnomusicology talk, circa 1975, Given at Festival of American Folklife (Box-folder 20.02)
  - "In celebration of ethnicity," 1976, Article co-written with Susan Kalcik and published in Exchange, Summer 1976 (Box-folder 20.03)
  - "Folk arts" article, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 20.04)
  - Hawaii Council on the Arts, 1981 (Box-folder 20.05)
  - "Preserving folk arts: the National Endowment for the Arts," 1981, Written for Festival of American Folklife program book (Box-folder 20.06)
  - Smithsonian Festival brochure, 1982, Text for brochure. (Box-folder 20.07)
  - Music Educators Journal article, 1983 (Box-folder 20.08)
  - "U.S. public policy for the folk arts," 1983-1986, Presentation given at the East-West Center (Box-folder 20.09)
  - "Folklore and power" conference paper, 1983-1988, Presentation at Fife Conference (Box-folder 20.10)
  - "What shall we do about the folk arts?," 1984, Texas Folkore Society speech (Box-folder 20.11)
  - "Folk arts and aging," 1984, NEA speech (Box-folder 20.12)
  - "Just an incredible country we live in," 1984, Bess Lomax Hawes was interviewed by Boris Weintraub for this publication (Box-folder 20.13)
  - "Aspects of federal folklife" in Practicing Anthropology, 1985 (Box-folder 20.14)
  - Smithsonian Festival opening remarks, 1985 (Box-folder 20.15)
  - "Hindsight and forethought," 1985, Public Sector Folklore meeting (Box-folder 20.16)
  - Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe, 1985, Cultural Forum in Budapest, two speeches (Box-folder 20.17)
  - "The growth of the profession of folkore," 1985-1986, Social Science (Box-folder 20.18)
  - Article for Journal of Human Values and Aging, 1987 (Box-folder 20.19)
  - "Beyond necessity" speech, Philadelphia, 1989, Presentation given at Balch institute on February 11, 1989 (Box-folder 20.20)
  - Aging, 1999-2002 (Box-folder 20.21)
  - "Practice makes perfect," 1992, Society for Ethnomusicology conference; also published in Ethnomusicology, Fall 1992 (Box-folder 20.22)
  - University of North Carolina speech and publication, 1989-1991, Regarding keynote speech given at UNC conference in 1989; subsequent publication in book -- Songs of the South, 1991 (Box-folder 20.23)
  - National Council on the Arts Missouri speech, 1988 (Box-folder 20.24)
  - National Assembly of State Arts Agencies speech, San Francisco, 1988 (Box-folder 20.25)
  - Museum of International Folk Arts, Santa Fe, 1988 (Box-folder 20.26)
  - American Folklore Society speeches, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 20.27)
  - "Remember the arts," 1990, Folklife Center News (Box-folder 20.28)
  - Library of Congress speech, 1990 (Box-folder 20.29)
  - "Why folk art," Ithaca, New York, speech, 1990 (Box-folder 20.30)
  - Missouri Arts Council speech, 1990 (Box-folder 20.31)
  - "Some characteristics and qualities of the folk arts" speech, New Jersey/Colorado, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 21.01)
  - "Melting pots and mosaics," Hawaii conference, 1991 (Box-folder 21.02)
  - "Funding African-American folk arts," 1991, Included in The arts of black folk: the arts of black folk conference for community organizations: presenting African American folk arts, published by Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture (Box-folder 21.03)
  - National Council meeting, 1991 (Box-folder 21.04)
  - "Multiculturalism" University of Wisconsin speech, 1993 (Box-folder 21.05)
  - "Apprenticing in the folk arts," creative marriages, traditional arts apprenticeship, 1991-1998 (Box-folder 21.06)
  - "Reminiscences and exhortations," 1993-1995, Seeger lecture for Society for Ethnomusicology; originally written for SEM lecture and subsequently repurposed as article in Ethnomusicology, Spring/Summer 1995 (Box-folder 21.07)
  - "Taking a breath," 1994, Published in New York Folklore, Vol. XXI no. 1-2, 1995 (Box-folder 21.08)
  - "Speaking to teachers"/Musics of Hawaii, 1994, Speaking to Teachers article was published in Musics of Hawai'i: "It All Comes from the Heart" -- An Anthology of Musical Traditions in Hawai'i (Box-folder 21.09)
  - "Cowboy poetry and song: collecting and recollecting" Colorado/Nevada, 1985-1996, Written for "cowboy poetry connection program" (Box-folder 21.10)
  - "Let's talk about aesthetics," 1995, Maine Arts Sponsors Association (Box-folder 21.11)
  - Rinzler celebration remarks, Highlander, Tennessee, 1995 (Box-folder 21.12)
  - Sustainable Folklore conference opening remarks, 1995 (Box-folder 21.13)
  - "U.S. policies and cultural continuity" speech for International Council for Traditional World Music Conference, 1995 (Box-folder 21.14)
  - Appalachian State speech, 1995 (Box-folder 21.15)
  - "That which endures" speech at Humboldt conference, circa 1995 (Box-folder 21.16)
  - "When we were joyful," circa 1995 (Box-folder 21.17)
  - Denver speech, Chicano Humanities and Arts Council, 1995 (Box-folder 21.18)
  - Arlington, VA, civic celebration remarks, circa 1996 (Box-folder 21.19)
  - "Archives and activism: aspects of reciprocity between scholarly and local communities," 1997, Society for Ethnomusicology (Box-folder 21.20)
  - California State University, Northridge, Archive remarks, 1998 (Box-folder 21.21)
  - "Folk arts in the forefront: the agenda for the year 2000," 1997, Conference remarks (Box-folder 21.22)
  - Gene Autry Museum speech, 1999 (Box-folder 21.23)
  - Ruth Crawford Seeger talk, New York City, 2001 (Box-folder 21.24)
  - "Yeast to Make the Bread Rise," 1999-2002, Children's Music Network; published in Grantmakers in the Arts Reader, Fall 2002 (Box-folder 21.25)
  - Speeches, 1967-1995 (Box-folder 21.26)
  - Writings, 1968-1995 (Box-folder 21.27)
  - Autobiography of Bess Lomax Hawes -- Administrative, 2006, Regarding Bess Lomax Hawes's autobiography, Sing It Pretty (Box-folder 22.01)
  - Sing It Pretty, Correspondence, 2007-2009 (Box-folder 22.02)
  - Step It Down, Harper/Row: Fran McCullough, 1969-1975, McCullough was Hawes's editor on Step It Down (Box-folder 22.03)
  - Step It Down, Harper/Row: Alfred E. Prettyman, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 22.04)
  - Step It Down, Collins-Knowlton-Wing, Inc., Josephine Rogers, 1975, Rogers was Hawes's literary agent (Box-folder 22.05)
  - Step It Down, Notes and data, circa 1967 (Box-folder 22.06)
  - "Pretty little girl" -- handwritten, transcribed music, circa 1970 (Box-folder 22.07)
  - Musical notation, notebook (1 of 2), circa 1970 (Box-folder 22.08)
  - Musical notation, notebook (2 of 2), circa 1970 (Box-folder 22.09)
  - Musical notation (1 of 3), circa 1970 (Box-folder 22.10)
  - Musical notation (2 of 3), circa 1970 (Box-folder 22.11)
  - Musical notation (3 of 3), circa 1970 (Box-folder 22.12)
  - Transcribed music and lyrics (1 of 2), circa 1965 (Box-folder 22.13)
  - Transcribed music and lyrics (2 of 2), circa 1965 (Box-folder 22.14)
  - Step It Down correspondence, miscellaneous, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 22.15)
  - Step It Down contracts and clearances, 1963-1982 (Box-folder 22.16)
  - Remaindering, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 23.01)
  - Step It Down paperback, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 23.02)
  - Step It Down University of Georgia Press, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 23.03)
  - Step It Down Reviews and Correspondence, 1965-1975, Includes correspondence from Alan Lomax and Pete and Toshi Seeger (Box-folder 23.04)
  - Bessie Jones Transcriptions, 1961 (Box-folder 23.05)
  - Bessie Jones transcriptions, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 23.06)
  - Bessie Jones estate, 1987-2002 (Box-folder 23.07)
  - John Avery Lomax papers at University of Texas at Austin, 1961-1976 (Box-folder 23.08)
  - John Avery Lomax papers at University of Texas at Austin, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 23.09)
  - John Avery Lomax papers at University of Texas at Austin, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 23.10)
  - Bess Bauman-Brown Lomax correspondence, 1924-1965 (Box-folder 24.01)
  - John A. Lomax, 1948-1998, Includes official memorandum from Texas Governor John Connally recognizing John A. Lomax removed to oversize box. (Box-folder 24.02)
  - Ruby Terrill Lomax (Deanie), 1935-1998 (Box-folder 24.03)
  - Shirley Lomax Mansell, 1913-1996 (Box-folder 24.04)
  - Letters and clippings, 1927-1997 (Box-folder 24.05)
  - John Lomax, Jr. (Umpty), 1938-1993, Includes some copies of The Cotton Rag, published by the Houston Folklore Society, removed to oversize box. (Box-folder 24.06)
  - Margaret "Mimi" Lomax, 1942-1970 (Box-folder 24.07)
  - John Lomax III (Marable), 1981-1997 (Box-folder 24.08)
  - Bess Brown Lomax’s scrapbook, circa 1900-1920, Bess Bauman-Brown Lomax materials (Box-folder 24.09)
  - Joe Lomax, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 24.10)
  - Writings by John A. Lomax and Bess Bauman-Brown Lomax (1 of 2), circa 1903-1994, This folder contains the contents of a scrapbook (Box-folder 25.01)
  - Writings by John A. Lomax and Bess Bauman-Brown Lomax (2 of 2), circa 1903-1994, This folder contains the contents of a scrapbook (Box-folder 25.02)
  - John A. Lomax – letters, 1901-1947 (Box-folder 25.03)
  - John A. Lomax Gathering (1 of 2), 1971-1993 (Box-folder 25.04)
  - John A. Lomax Gathering (2 of 2), 1987-1997 (Box-folder 25.05)
  - Nolan Porterfield book on John A. Lomax, 1994, Regarding Last Cavalier: The Life and Times of John A. Lomax, 1867-1948 (Box-folder 25.06)
  - Sister Virginia Margaret correspondence, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 25.07)
  - Personal miscellany, 1966-2006 (Box-folder 25.08)
  - Letters to Naomi, 1964-1969 (Box-folder 25.09)
  - Seeger, 1954-1964, Mostly correspondence about Pete and Toshi Seeger's travels through Eastern Europe (Box-folder 25.10)
  - Seeger, 1955-1965, Mostly about Pete Seeger's appearance before the House Un-American Activities Committee and subsequent indictment for contempt of Congress (Box-folder 25.11)
  - Bess Brown Lomax: letters and information about the child Bess Lomax Hawes, 1927-1930 (Box-folder 26.01)
  - Alan Lomax-- family correspondence, 1955-1996, Miscellaneous topics, including American Patchwork TV series and the Global Jukebox project, Alan Lomax's power of attorney and an essay written by Alan Lomax--"Unity and Diversity: a Sudanese Cultural Program" (Box-folder 26.02)
  - Rounder’s The Alan Lomax Collection, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 26.03)
  - Alan Lomax—writings, 1975-1993, Includes "Culture-style factors in face-to-face interaction," Song as a Measure of People, Folk Music in the Roosevelt White House, "Singing" entry in Encyclopedia Britannica, "A General Theory," "An Appeal for Cultural Equity," "A Future for Anthropology: Aesthetic Anthropology," and documents about the Smithsonian Festival of American Folklife (Box-folder 26.04)
  - Alan Lomax—professional, 1969-1997 (Box-folder 26.05)
  - "Black Style in American Pop Music"—Alan Lomax, 1988 (Box-folder 26.06)
  - C.C. Mansell house plans, 1940, Blueprints removed to oversize box. (Box-folder 26.07)
  - Alan Lomax, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 26.08)
  - Bess Brown Lomax alphabet certificate, 1924 (Box-folder 27.01)
  - Book of verses made up by Bess Brown Lomax, Jr., 1925-1928 (Box-folder 27.02)
  - Bess's early writing: "Just 1930," 1930 (Box-folder 27.03)
  - Bess's early writing: "Eastwick: a community survey," 1941, Term paper for Bryn Mawr sociology course (Box-folder 27.04)
  - Bess’s early writing: "Recipe for a Halloween party," circa 1929 (Box-folder 27.05)
  - Family history, circa 1925 (Box-folder 27.06)
  - Shirley’s Book by Bess Bauman Brown Lomax, 1907-1990 (Box-folder 27.07)
  - John A. Lomax letters to Shirley regarding Bess—copies (1935-1938), circa 1995 (Box-folder 27.08)
  - Bess’s singing and typing lessons, circa 1925-1930 (Box-folder 27.09)
  - Butch—notes, circa 1960-1971, Notes about art (Box-folder 28.01)
  - Butch—notes, 1961, Notes about art (Box-folder 28.02)
  - Butch—notes, 1962, Notes about art; handwritten timeline of events in English history from fourteenth through sixteenth century removed to oversize box. (Box-folder 28.03)
  - Butch’s art – family notes, circa 1960-1973 (Box-folder 28.04)
  - Butch – song and book contracts, 1944-1966 (Box-folder 28.05)
  - Butch – legal, 1919-1987, Includes birth certificate, electrical welding trade school certificate, general commercial photography certificate and voter registration form for Butch (Baldwin Hawes) (Box-folder 28.06)
  - Notes following death of Butch Hawes 1971-1972, Includes birth and death certificates in addition to condolence letters, telegrams, poetry and obituaries. (Box-folder 28.06a)
  - Household accounts, Topanga, Canyon, 1953-1959 (Box-folder 28.07)
  - Bess Lomax Hawes academic records, 1936-1970 (Box-folder 28.08)
  - Politics, 1982-1995 (Box-folder 28.09)
  - Bess at Office of War Information (1945), circa 2000, Regarding accusations of Communist sympathies and subsequent recommendation for dismissal from position as Acting Chief of the Music Division of OWI Radio Overseas (Box-folder 28.10)
  - Ted Carpenter correspondence, 1967-1988 (Box-folder 28.11)
  - John A. Lomax business, 1987-1998 (Box-folder 28.12)
  - Bess -- personal correspondence, 1940-2009 (Box-folder 28.13)
  - Peter Hurd mural fresco event, 1989 (Box-folder 28.14)
  - Postcards and cards collected and received, 1979-1997 (Box-folder 28.15)
  - Recorded quotes, circa 1988 (Box-folder 29.01)
  - Mechanical license for "Arthritic Blues," 2006 (Box-folder 29.02)
  - Socialization seminar, 1969-1970, Taken at UC Berkeley with Naomi (Box-folder 29.03)
  - Alan Lomax archive, 2007 (Box-folder 29.04)
  - Family clippings from Shirley, circa 1947-2008 (Box-folder 29.05)
  - Passport, birth, marriage, voting documents, 1921-1995 (Box-folder 29.06)
  - Santa Monica house, 1985, Photos removed to folder 35.06 in Series III. (Box-folder 29.07)
  - Family tree, circa 2005 (Box-folder 29.08)
  - Bess Lomax Hawes interview with David King Dunaway (1977), 1977-1978 (Box-folder 29.09)
  - Bess Lomax Hawes condolences and obituaries, 2009 (Box-folder 29.10)
  - Responses to Bess Lomax Hawes's death (1 of 2), 2009 (Box-folder 29.11)
  - Responses to Bess Lomax Hawes's death (2 of 2), 2009 (Box-folder 29.12)
  - Bess Lomax Hawes biographical, 2007-2009 (Box-folder 30.01)
  - Hawes family history (1878-1996), circa 1960-1996 (Box-folder 30.02)
  - Lomax book rights -- estate settlement, 1974-1999 (Box-folder 30.03)
  - Lomax estate settlement, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 30.04)
  - Lomax estate settlement, 1948-1969 (Box-folder 30.05)
  - Bess Bauman Brown's bible, 1897-1903, The Holy Bible, containing the Old and New Testaments, Oxford, printed at the University Press, The S. S. Teacher's Edition, circa 1890. Inscribed: "Bessie Bauman Brown from Auntie, Christmas 1897." Also includes a handwritten list of bible verses. (Box-folder 30.06)
  - Sound recordings documentation: sound tape reels, circa 1960-1975 (Box-folder 31.01)
  - Sound recordings documentation: sound cassettes, circa 1975-2003 (Box-folder 31.02)
  - Sound recordings documentation: sound cassettes, circa 1975-2003 (Box-folder 31.03)
  - Moving images documentation, 1983-2008 (Box-folder 31.04)
- Series II: Sound recordings, Note: Track lists and other documentation exist for some sound recordings, and can be found in Series I, box 31.
  - Subseries A: Sound tape reels, Note: Many of the Sea Island Singers recordings are from summer workshops at Idyllwild Arts Foundation in Idyllwild, California.
    - Bess Hawes beginning guitar class, circa 1960 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR001)
    - Bessie Jones, Barbara Dane and Georgia Sea Island Singers, November 15, 1962 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR002)
    - Interview between Barbara Dane and Bessie Jones, November 15, 1962, After Folk Song Concert at San Fernando Valley State College. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR003)
    - Bess Hawes's beginning guitar class, 1963, Spring semester. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR004)
    - Idyllwild concert; summer, 1964 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR005)
    - Sea Island tape, 1965, Tape 5-2-B. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR006)
    - Sea Island Game tapes; Idyllwild, 1965, Tape 5-3. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR007)
    - Georgia Sea Island Children's Games, Idyllwild, 1965, Tape 5-4 AB; Tuesday, 2nd week. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR008)
    - Sea Island Children's Workshop, Idyllwild, 1965, Tape 5-5 AB; Thursday 2nd week (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR009)
    - Sea Island Childrens Games, Idyllwild, 1965, Tape 5-6 AB; Wednesday, 2nd week. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR010)
    - Sea Island; Interview at Ed Pearl's house, July 26, 1965, Tape 5-7, with Bessie and Emma. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR011)
    - Sea Island Singers; children's games, 1965, Tape 5-8-A; Fri. 2nd week. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR012)
    - Georgia Sea Islanders, July 29, 1965, Tape 5-9-AB. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR013)
    - Georgia Sea Islands, July 29, 1965, Tape 5-10-AB. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR014)
    - Georgia Sea Islands, August 3, 1965, Tape 5-11-AB; recorded at Fairview Hospital, last day of stay. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR015)
    - Tape #30, circa 1965 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR016)
    - Tape #31, circa 1965 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR017)
    - Tape #37, circa 1965 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR018)
    - Tape #38, circa 1965, Written on leader: Submitted by Joan E. Barber, Esthetics of Non-Literate Peoples, January, 1962; "This is All Our Water". (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR019)
    - Georgia Sea Island Singers at Idyllwild, circa 1965 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR020)
    - Bessie Jones, circa 1965, Tape Number 2. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR021)
    - Bessie Jones, circa 1965, Tape Number 3. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR022)
    - Bessie Jones, circa 1965, Tape Number 4. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR023)
    - Bessie Jones, circa 1965, Tape Number 5. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR024)
    - KPFK Hawes interview with Ed Cray, circa 1965 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR025)
    - Sea Island clapping; John Greenway program, University of Colorado, circa 1965-1967, Summer. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR026)
    - Negro children's games, November 2, 1967, 75th St school. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR027)
    - Georgia Sea Island Singers, May 21, 1969 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR028)
    - Georgia Sea Island Singers, May 21, 1969 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR029)
    - John Davis interview, Santa Monica, May, 1972, Note: "Both of us exhausted." (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR030)
    - Molokan tape, circa 1975, May be a sample tape. Bess brought the Molokans to the California Heartland segment of the Folklife Festival in Washington, DC, 1975 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR031)
    - Bessie Jones special dubs, circa 1965 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR032)
    - Dupe of 1965 recordings: Sea Island, circa 1965, Tape 5-5 AB. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR033)
  - Subseries B: Sound cassettes, Note: SR072-SR087 are likely recordings for an ethnomusicology course taught by Hawes at SFVSC.
    - Albanian folk music, from A. L. Lloyd; Chamarita, Cal RA 1975, 1975 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR034)
    - Micronesian Music Project sampler, Truk and Ponape; Kim Bailey, 1978-1979 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR035)
    - Pacific Trip August 1983, Hawaii/Guam, Raymond Kane, 1983 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR036)
    - 2nd tape of notes, Pacific trip, Saipan, 1983 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR037)
    - Bessie Jones funeral, sermon, graveside, psychic; Ko Nimo (Ghana), 1984 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR038)
    - Parsley, Sage and Politics: The Lives and Music of Peggy Seeger and Ewan MacColl, circa 1985, Side 1 and Side 2. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR039)
    - Parsley, Sage and Politics: The Lives and Music of Peggy Seeger and Ewan MacColl, circa 1985, Side 3 and Side 4. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR040)
    - Parsley, Sage and Politics: The Lives and Music of Peggy Seeger and Ewan MacColl, circa 1985, Side 5 and Side 6. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR041)
    - The Ballad of John Axon (#1), circa 1985 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR042)
    - Song of a Road (#2), circa 1985 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR043)
    - Singing the Fishing (#3), circa 1985 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR044)
    - The Big Hewer (#4), circa 1985 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR045)
    - The Body Blow (#5), circa 1985 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR046)
    - On the Edge (#6), circa 1985 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR047)
    - The Fight Game (#7), circa 1985 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR048)
    - The Travelling People (#8), circa 1985 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR049)
    - Bess's "Folklore and Power" lecture; Bess's Fife Honor Lecture, Logan, Utah, 1986 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR050)
    - South Carolina; prison interview; aerobics, 1986 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR051)
    - Secretarial #1, February 3, 1986 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR052)
    - Bess Lomax Hawes's talk, East-West Center, Honolulu, March 28, 1986 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR053)
    - Samoa, 1987 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR054)
    - Samoa II, February 28, 1987 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR055)
    - Bess Lomax Hawes and C. J. Johnson on WCDU, September 29, 1987 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR056)
    - Bess's trip to Bermuda, February, 1989 (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR057)
    - Cook Islands #1, 1992, Rarotonga Church and Atui. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR058)
    - Cook Islands #2, 1992, Festival Opening. (Tape-id AFC 2014/008: SR059)